<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching Assistant | Bernardo Rivas</title>
    <link>http://localhost:64452/tags/teaching-assistant/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:64452/tags/teaching-assistant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching Assistant</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:64452/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Teaching Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64452/tags/teaching-assistant/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Real Analysis (TA)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:64452/teaching/fa23_real-analysis-ta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:64452/teaching/fa23_real-analysis-ta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a teaching assistant for Introduction to Real Analysis, I supported students in understanding fundamental concepts of real analysis, including limits, continuity, differentiation, and integration. The course focused on developing rigorous mathematical reasoning and proof-writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responsibilities&#34;&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led weekly recitation sessions to reinforce lecture material and address student questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graded homework assignments and exams, providing detailed feedback to help students improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Held regular office hours to provide additional support and clarification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborated with the course instructor to develop effective teaching materials and assessments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-approach&#34;&gt;Teaching Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my recitation sessions, I focused on active problem-solving and conceptual understanding. I created additional practice problems that bridged the gap between routine exercises and more challenging proof-based questions. I encouraged students to articulate their reasoning clearly and precisely, emphasizing the importance of mathematical rigor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact&#34;&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students in my recitation sections showed improved performance on proof-writing tasks and demonstrated greater confidence in tackling complex problems. I received positive feedback for my clear explanations and approachable teaching style.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
