<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks | Bernardo Rivas</title>
    <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:51193/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:51193/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Dynamics in Systems Biology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/siam-ds25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/siam-ds25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk presented recent advances in understanding global dynamics in systems biology using combinatorial and topological methods. The presentation focused on applications of Conley Index Theory to gene regulatory networks and demonstrated how these mathematical frameworks can provide rigorous insights into complex biological systems with potential applications in ecology and population dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational dynamics of gene regulatory networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/dynamics-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/dynamics-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This seminar presented a computational approach to studying the dynamics of gene regulatory networks. The talk explored how mathematical models and computational tools can be used to analyze and predict the behavior of complex biological systems, with a focus on rigorous methods for identifying global dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network dynamics via combinatorics, topology and homology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/ams-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/ams-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This seminar explored the intersection of combinatorics, topology, and homology in the study of network dynamics. The presentation demonstrated how these mathematical frameworks can be combined to analyze complex networks, with applications to biological systems and gene regulatory networks. The talk highlighted recent advances in using algebraic topological methods to understand the global behavior of dynamical systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytical bounds for combinatorial topological dynamics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/montreal-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/montreal-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop presentation discussed analytical bounds for combinatorial topological dynamics, focusing on rigorous mathematical frameworks for understanding nonlinear dynamical systems. The talk explored how analytical techniques can be combined with combinatorial and topological methods to provide rigorous bounds on the behavior of complex systems, with applications to gene regulatory networks and other biological systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Computational Framework for Dynamics of Genetic Regulatory Networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/ams-eastern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/ams-eastern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This presentation introduced a computational framework for analyzing the dynamics of genetic regulatory networks. The talk discussed how mathematical models and computational tools can be used to understand the complex behavior of gene regulatory systems, with a focus on rigorous methods for identifying global dynamics. The framework combines combinatorial, topological, and analytical approaches to provide insights into the behavior of biological systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combinatorial topological method for gene regulatory networks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/leiden-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/leiden-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop presentation introduced a combinatorial topological method for analyzing gene regulatory networks. The talk explored how these mathematical frameworks can be used to understand the complex dynamics of high-dimensional biological networks. The presentation focused on obtaining rigorous analytical bounds to identify dynamical structures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rigorous numerics of invariant manifolds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51193/talks/summer-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51193/talks/summer-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This presentation discussed rigorous numerical methods for studying invariant manifolds in dynamical systems. The talk explored computational approaches that provide mathematically rigorous results about the structure and properties of invariant manifolds in differential equations. The presentation highlighted the importance of these techniques for understanding the global behavior of nonlinear dynamical systems and their bifurcations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
